# JACK MAHONEY

## CHICAGO, IL

Phone Number: 517-574-8060 Email: mahonei79@gmail.com LinkedIn: Jack's Profile GitHub: Jack's GitHub

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Jack is a technology professional with a background in cybersecurity, information technology (IT) services, software engineering and electrical engineering. Jack has over 4 years of experience in advising clients with optimization, end-user experience, risk analysis, and organization maturity for their respective IT operations as they navigate through securing their network, cost saving exercises, mitigating risk, contract negotiations, and performance improvement projects. His commitment remains to improving client experience and continuing to develop the skills necessary to be a well rounded full stack engineer.

#### **SKILLS**

Software: JavaScript, TypeScript, CSS, HTML, React, Redux, SQL, C, Pspice

Expertise: Project Management, Enterprise Architecture, Risk Assessments, Software Licensing (Oracle Licensing SME),

Configuration Management and Change Management, Cyber Recovery Services

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Cybersecurity Risk Management Lead, Infrastructure - Northern Trust - Chicago IL

August 2022 - Present

- Led project for preparation of 2023 Federal cybersecurity assessment. Project consisted of collaborating with stakeholders and conducting gap analysis of current state operations and procedures in alignment to Federal requirements
- Oversaw the Issue Management Program for identifying, tracking, and closing technology related Audit and non-Audit issues
  that pose inherent risk to the cybersecurity of the organization. The process consisted of working with responsible
  stakeholders to understand the associated risk of the identified issue and develop workstreams to evidence the mitigation of
  said risk

### Cybersecurity Senior Consultant - Optiv Security - Chicago, IL

July 2021 - August 2022

- Maximized cybersecurity maturity and IT asset value by helping clients understand business sectors for improvement based on NIST and ISO 27001 standards, licensing rules that create compliance risk, unnecessary spending, top cyber threats to the network (internal and external), securing the Software and Development Lifecycle (SDLC), and how the IT Asset Lifecycle fits into each organization's cybersecurity practice
- Identified and provided key technical and strategic initiatives such as network segregation and secure software deployment to improve overall maturity relative to leading Optiv security frameworks, all while reducing risks across the enterprise
- Operated as a full time resource to support financial services CISO in day to day operations. Responsibilities included strategic planning for future state goals, current state risk mitigation, project management of cybersecurity initiatives, and oversight of Identity and Access Management program

#### Cyber Risk Consultant & Senior Consultant - Deloitte - Chicago, IL

January 2019 - July 2021

- Served multiple Fortune 500 clients, as well as other clients in a diverse array of industries, including the Financial Sector,
   Semiconductors & Electrical Components, Healthcare, Athletic Apparel, and the Education Sector on how to reduce overall cyber risk by leveraging industry leading practices for Asset Management at the foundational level
- Assessed data feeds and outputs to produce endpoint completeness summary to determine size of client's global endpoint footprint
- Assisted in implementation of ServiceNow Software Asset Management Professional (SAM Pro) within client's existing ServiceNow CMDB; various activities occurred including data validation, data normalization, and tool configuration

### **INTERESTS**

API Management, Product Design with Figma (UI / UX),, Microservices, C# and .NET Framework, Network Proxy Security

#### **EDUCATION**

Michigan State University | Bachelor of Science: Electrical Engineering